They were never alone.
Smurfs: The Lost Village is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Kelly Asbury.
In this fully animated, all-new take on the Smurfs, a mysterious map sets Smurfette and her friends Brainy, Clumsy and Hefty on
an exciting race through the Forbidden Forest leading to the discovery of the biggest secret in Smurf history.
Smurfette (voice), played by Demi Lovato.
Gargamel (voice), played by Rainn Wilson.
Hefty (voice), played by Joe Manganiello.
Clumsy (voice), played by Jack McBrayer.
Brainy (voice), played by Danny Pudi.
Papa Smurf (voice), played by Mandy Patinkin.
Smurfs: The Lost Village is a 2017 American animated fantasy adventure comedy film
based on The Smurfs comic series by the Belgian comics artist Peyo.
A reboot of Sony Pictures Animation's previous live-action animated hybrid films, the film was directed by Kelly Asbury and written by Stacey Harman and Pamela Ribon, and stars the
voices of Demi Lovato, Rainn Wilson, Joe Manganiello, Jack McBrayer, Danny Pudi, Michelle Rodriguez, Ellie Kemper, Ariel Winter, Mandy Patinkin
and Julia Roberts.
In the film, a mysterious map prompts Smurfette, Brainy, Clumsy, and
Hefty to find a lost village before Gargamel does.
On May 10, 2012, two weeks after they announced production of The Smurfs 2, Columbia Pictures and Sony Pictures
Animation were already developing a script for The Smurfs 3, with writers Karey Kirkpatrick and Chris Poche.
Plans for a third live-action film was cancelled in favor of an animated reboot.
Kelly Asbury was confirmed as director in March 2014, and the voice
cast was announced throughout the first half of 2015.
The film is dedicated to Jonathan Winters, the voice actor of both Grandpa Smurf from the 1980s animated series and Papa Smurf from the original movie series who died in
2013, as well as Anton Yelchin, the voice actor of Clumsy Smurf in the live-action movies, and Nine Culliford, the wife of Peyo, both of whom died in 2016.
Smurfs: The Lost Village was theatrically released in the United
States on April 7, 2017, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and grossed
$197 million against a $60 million budget.
A computer-animated Smurfs series inspired by The Lost Village premiered in 2021,
while a further animated reboot, titled Smurfs, was released in 2025.
The tone is lighthearted.